双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译     Rucle
翻译   泰温公爵
翻译   波隆史铎克渥斯
君临 King's Landing
翻译    凯冯・兰尼斯特
Red Keep
红堡
校对    临冬城的狮子
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
校对   Barossa
奔流城 Riverrun
Riverrun
城
流
奔
复校    托曼・兰尼斯特
复校   泰温公爵
临冬城 Winterfell
复校   imzxz1051
监制    临冬城的狮子
后期   poplar
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
阿斯塔波Astapor
原著  乔治・R・R・马丁
《冰与火之歌》 改编
根据长篇小说
权力的游戏
第三季 第三集
衣柜字幕组
第三集  "Walk of Punishment"
惩罚之路
霍斯特・徒利
前奔流城公爵 凯特琳・徒利之父
凯特琳・徒利
艾德・史塔克的遗孀
艾德慕・徒利
奔流城公爵 凯特琳・徒利之弟
泰丽莎・梅吉尔
小护士 罗柏的王后
罗柏・史塔克
北境之王
布林登・徒利
“黑鱼”  凯特琳・徒利之叔
恕我冒昧 外甥
If I may, nephew,
想当初我和一个副官在石磨坊打仗
I encountered a situation with one of my lieutenants
那可是场――
at the Stone Mill which may have some bearing--
你怎么还要提那该死的石磨坊？
Why don't you shut your mouth about that damned mill?
还有你别叫他“外甥” 他是你的国王
And don't call him "nephew." He is your king.
罗柏知道我并非有意对他不敬――
Robb knows I meant him no disr--
我不是你的国王真算你走运
You're lucky I'm not your king.
我不会允许你把自己的蠢行
I wouldn't let you wave your blunders around
当成胜利四处宣扬
like a victory flag.
是我的蠢行让泰温的疯狗
My blunder sent Tywin's mad dog
夹着尾巴逃回了凯岩城
scurrying back to Casterly Rock with his tail between his legs.
我想罗柏国王明白 光他一个人打胜仗
I think King Robb understands we're not gonna win this war
我们是赢不了这场战争的
if he's the only one winning any battles.
所以 这场胜利的荣耀足够我宣扬了吧
No, there's glory enough to go around.
这与荣耀无关
It's not about glory.
你收到的指令是等他主动出击
Your instructions were to wait for him to come to you.
可我抓住了一个机会
I seized an opportunity.
那这磨坊有什么价值吗？
What value was the mill?
魔山想要从那过河
The Mountain was garrisoned across the river from it.
那他现在在那儿？
Is he there now?
当然不在 我们拦截了他
Of course not. We took the fight to him.
他打不过我们
He could not withstand us.
我本想诱敌西入
I wanted to draw the Mountain into the west,
在我们的地盘上 就可以趁机剿灭他
into our country where we could surround him and kill him
我故意让他追赶我们
I wanted him to chase us,
他会这么做的
which he would have done because he is a mad dog
因为他就是一条没脑子的疯狗
without a strategic thought in his head.
我原本可以把他的脑袋插到木桩上
I could have that head on a spike by now.
可是我现在只有个磨坊
Instead, I have a mill.
我们有人质
We took hostages.
威廉・兰尼斯特 马丁・兰尼斯特
Willem Lannister. Martyn Lannister.
他们两个才14岁
Willem and Martyn Lannister are 14 years old.
我想马丁是15岁
Martyn is 15, I believe.
我的两个妹妹在泰温・兰尼斯特手上
Tywin Lannister has my sisters.
我有求和吗？
Have I sued for peace?
没有
No.
那你认为他会
Do you think he'll sue for peace
因为他父亲的
because we have his father's
兄弟的重孙子来求和吗？
brother's great-grandsons?
不会
No.
你们损失了多少人？
How many men did you lose?
208.
可是我们每战死一人 兰尼斯特就――
But for every man we lost, the Lannisters--
我们比泰温更缺人！
We need our men more than Tywin needs his!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 我不知道 - 你本该知道
- I didn't know. - You would have.
要是刚才我们交流时你能给点耐心
Right here today at this gathering if you had been patient.
看起来这里可没几个人有耐心了
We seem to be running short of patience here.
你们知道谁有耐心么？
You know who isn't?
泰温・兰尼斯特
Tywin Lannister.
培提尔・贝里席
“小指头” 财政大臣
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
派席尔
大学士
提利昂・兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
泰温・兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
这桌子可真贴心可爱
Intimate. Lovely table.
椅子也比小议会厅的好
Better chairs than the old small council chamber.
跟共事的大臣们也真够近 这我喜欢
Conveniently close to your own quarters. I like it.
有詹姆的消息了吗？
What news of Jaime?
2万低贱的北方人
20,000 unwashed Northerners
都知道他已经失踪了好几周了
have known about his escape for weeks.
总体来说 我们掌握的密探和信息
Collectively, you control more spies and informants
比其他所有人都多
than the rest of the world combined.
你们是想告诉我 你们当中没有一个人
Do you mean to tell me that none of you
知道他在哪里吗？
has any notion of where he is?
- 我们正在尽力 大人  - 那就尽全力
- We are trying, my lord. - Try harder.
那目前我们知道什么？
What do we have, then?
罗柏・史塔克还有他大部分军队正在奔流城
Robb Stark and most of his bannermen are in Riverrun
给他外祖父霍斯特・徒利举办葬礼
for the funeral of his grandfather Lord Hoster Tully.
史塔克不在的时候 赫伦堡由卢斯・波顿镇守
In Stark's absence, Roose Bolton holds Harrenhal,
这样一来 他就是事实上的赫伦堡公爵
which would seem to make him Lord of Harrenhal,
- 只是少个头衔罢了  - 随便 让他占着吧
- in practice if not in name. - Well, let him have it.
赫伦堡公爵的头衔
The name suits our purposes
比起一堆废墟来说 对我们更有用
far more than that useless pile of rubble.
赫伦堡公爵将会是艾林家寡妇理想的配偶
The Lord of Harrenhal will make a worthy suitor for the widow Arryn.
对此我对您心怀感激 大人
For which I am extremely grateful to you, my lord.
艾林夫人和我青梅竹马
Lady Arryn and I have known each other since we were children.
她总是……
She has always been...
对我有好感
positively predisposed toward me.
如果求婚成功
A successful courtship would make Lord Baelish
贝里席大人将会成为谷地的主人
acting Lord of the Vale.
一职生多职 倒是一点都不错
Titles do seem to breed titles.
你要前往艾林谷 越快越好
You'll leave for the Eyrie as soon as possible
把莱莎・艾林管住
and bring Lysa Arryn into the fold.
这样少狼主就要把自己的小阿姨给
Then the young wolf can add his own aunt to the list
列为敌人了
of people who have taken up arms against him.
我可无意于阻止真爱重逢啊
Far be it from me to hinder true love,
不过贝里席大人的离开会带来一定的问题
but Lord Baelish's absence would present certain problems.
国王的婚礼 这项空前浩大的盛事
The royal wedding may end up
会因此夭折
being the most expensive event in living memory.
夏天已经结束了 艰苦的日子还在前头呢
Summer has ended, hard days lie ahead.
现在把王室的财务搁置起来可不合适
Not a good time to leave the crown's finances unattended.
完全赞同
Fully agreed.
所以我要命你担任新的财务大臣
Which is why I'm naming you new Master of Coin.
财务大臣？
Master of Coin?
这将会是最适合你的位置
It would appear to be a position that best suits your talents.
花钱我倒是很会
I'm quite good at spending money,
虽然我这辈子都腰缠万贯
but a lifetime of outrageous wealth
但没学会怎么理财
hasn't taught me much about managing it.
我一点都不怀疑你会证明自己能胜任这个挑战
I have no doubt you will prove equal to this challenge.
同意 同意
Hear, hear.
把她举在空中
He lifted her high in the air
他笑着喊着跟着香味在着弄
He sniffed and roared and smelled her there
遍踢遍喊 少女惊恐
She kicked and wailed, a maid so fair
可他舔蜂蜜的发丛
But he licked the honey from her hair
这头儿 那儿弄
From there to here, from here to there
全身黑棕 罩着毛绒
All black and brown and covered with hair
他跟随夏日里的气涌
He smelled that girl in the summer air
狗熊 狗熊 少女美容
The bear, the bear and the maiden fair...
这下你高兴啦
I hope you're pleased.
詹姆・兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
如果你当初给我武器 他们就不会把我们抓了
If you had armed me, they never would have taken us.
我们被抓的时候你不是带着武器么
You were armed when we were taken.
你不记得我当时被锁起来了么
I was in chains if you recall.
要不是我的手被捆住了
Our little match would have ended quite quick
布蕾妮・塔斯
“美人” 詹姆的保护者
我们的比试早就结束了
if my hands weren't bound.
我从小到大都听到说
All my life I've been hearing, "Jaime Lannister,
“詹姆・兰尼斯特是个多么杰出的剑客”
what a brilliant swordsman."
你比我想象中要慢
You were slower than I expected.
而且也没那么难以预测
And more predictable.
那是因为我在满是淤泥的牢笼里
I've been sitting in a muddy pen
被铁链锁了整整一年
wrapped in chains for the past year.
我可是个女人 照样把你给打败了
And I'm a woman. I was still beating you.
你可没有打败我
You were not beating me.
或许你是有像人们传说中那么厉害……
Maybe you were as good as people said...
曾经是
once.
或许人们只是喜欢鼓吹有名气的人
Or maybe people just love to overpraise a famous name.
今晚我们扎营的时候 你就会被强奸
When we make camp tonight, you'll be raped.
还不止一次
More than once.
这些伙计可从没见过贵族女人
None of these fellows have ever been with a noblewoman.
你最好别反抗
You'd be wise not to resist.
- 是吗？ - 他们会打断你的牙
- Would I? - They'll knock your teeth out.
你以为我会在乎自己的牙？
You think I care about my teeth?
不 我不管你是不是在乎自己的牙齿
No, I don't think you care about your teeth.
如果反抗 他们会宰了你
If you fight them, they will kill you.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
对他们有价值的犯人是我 而不是你
I'm the prisoner of value, not you.
他们要怎样就怎样好了 有什么要紧？
Let them have what they want. What does it matter?
- 有什么要紧？ - 闭上你的眼睛
- What does it matter? - Close your eyes.
假装他们是蓝礼
Pretend they're Renly.
如果你是个女人 你就不会反抗？
If you were a woman, you wouldn't resist?
你就会让他们蹂躏？
You'd let them do what they wanted?
如果我是个女人 我就让他们杀了我
If I was a woman, I'd make them kill me.
幸亏我不是 感谢诸神
But I'm not, thank the gods.
如果有像样的熔炉 我可以把它搞得跟新的一样
If I had a proper forge, I could make it good as new.
詹德利
“大牛” 铁匠学徒
没必要弄的多漂亮
Doesn't have to look pretty.
密尔的索罗斯
无旗兄弟会的红袍僧
只要能挡掉射过来的箭就可以了
It just has to keep the arrows out of my heart.
你为什么要帮他？
Why are you helping him?
他俘虏我们 现在又成了我们的朋友？
He takes us prisoner and now he's our friend?
你可不是我的俘虏 小小姐
You're not our prisoner, little lady.
艾莉亚・史塔克
- 那我是什么？ - 我们的客人
- What am I? - Our guest.
没有人把你锁起来
No one's put any chains on you.
那我可以走了么？
So I can walk away, then?
这片森林对奈德・史塔克的女儿来说可不安全
These woods aren't safe for Ned Stark's daughter.
被我们找到算你走运
You're lucky we found you.
你以为自己很会射箭嘛 小孬种？
You think you're good with that bow, you little twat?
比你见过的任何人都要好
Better than anyone you've ever met.
这是懦夫的武器
A coward's weapon.
我喜欢近身搏斗
I like to fight up close.
我喜欢在我捅进别人身体的时候看着他的脸
I like to see a man's face when I put the steel in him.
安盖
“射手” 来自风暴地的弓箭手
桑铎・克里冈
“猎狗”
为什么？那你就可以吻他了？
Why? So you can kiss him?
你还记得上一次你在这儿的时候？
You remember the last time you were here?
跟路上遇到的破烂酒馆都一个样
Looks like every other shit inn on the road.
不好意思 但是你实在太他妈丑了
Now, apologies, but you're one ugly fucker
还是不要让我看见你的脸
and I'd rather not see you no more.
悠着点啊
Watch your head.
走咯
Off we go.
出发！
Walk up!
你干嘛呢？ 我们要走了
What are you doing? We're about to leave.
我要留在这
I'm staying.
什么？
You're what?
“热派”
我给酒馆老板烤了些黄面包
I baked some brown bread for the innkeep
她说这是她吃过最好的
and she said she never had better.
她告诉索罗斯要把我留下
Told Thoros she's keeping me as a payment
作为一直给他提供免费食物的报酬
for all the free meals she's given him.
反正兄弟会又不想要我
Anyway, it's not me the Brotherhood wants.
我的兄弟可不是国王
My brother ain't no king.
我也不是凝冬城的史塔克
I'm not a Stark of Winterhell.
临冬城
Winterfell.
- 真的？ - 当然
- You sure? - I'm sure.
还有 这个是给你做的
Well, I made you something.
这是什么？
What is it?
是个狼啊
It's a wolf.
没错 是个狼
Yes, it is.
这是它的尾巴？
That's the tail?
是啊
Yeah.
好了 注意安全
Well, be safe.
嗯 你也是
Yeah, you, too.
别受伤
Don't get stabbed.
你也……
You don't...
别烧到手指
burn your fingers.
再见 热派
Good-bye, Hot Pie.
再见 阿利
Good-bye, Arry.
上马吧 小小姐
Up you go, little lady.
喂 热派
Hey, Hot Pie.
真的很好吃
It's really good.
某人居然忘记了有仗在打
A person could almost be forgiven
这可不好原谅啊
for forgetting we're at war.
对于世界上大部分地方来说 即便处于战争最黑暗的时期
It often comforts me to think that even in war's darkest days,
也根本什么都没有发生
in most places in the world
这样想常会让我心里安慰许多
absolutely nothing is happening.
我很想念你 叔叔
I've missed you, Uncle.
你离开这么久
Father missed you, too,
父亲也很想念你
from the day you left.
或许他从来没有说出来过――
Maybe he never said it in so many words--
或许？
Maybe?
你父亲是头顽固的老公牛
Your father was a stubborn old ox.
他死的时候我很惊讶
I was surprised when he died.
还以为死神对他没有那个耐性
Didn't think death had the patience.
你当时能陪在他身边实在太好了
I'm glad you were with him.
我多希望诸神让我当时也能在场
I wish to the gods I had been.
你们最终和解了吗？
Did you make peace in the end?
吵了三十年
After 30 years of fighting,
大概他已经不记得最初是因为什么了
I don't think he remembered what started it.
他叫我别再自称黑鱼
He asked me to stop calling myself Blackfish.
他说那是个老掉牙的笑话
He said it was an old joke
而且从一开始就不好笑
and it was never funny to begin with.
我告诉他 人们早已习惯叫我黑鱼
I told him people had been calling me Blackfish
这么长时间之后 我的本名都被忘了
for so long, they don't remember my real name.
每次他离开奔流城去君临
Every time he would leave for the capital
或者去参加比武大会
or fight in a campaign,
我都会看着他离开
I'd see him off.
他会说 “等着我回来 小凯特”
"Wait for me, little Cat," he'd say.
“等着我
"Wait for me
我很快就会回来的”
and I'll come back to you."
每天太阳升起的时候
And I would sit at this window
我就坐在这个窗边等他
every day when the sun came up, waiting.
我常常想
I wonder
布兰和瑞肯有多少次
how many times did Bran or Rickon
在眺望临冬城的旷野
stare across the moors of Winterfell
等着我回去
waiting for me to return.
我再也见不到他们了
I will never see them again.
别这么想
You mustn't think it.
我们还不知道确切情况
We don't know the truth.
他们可能藏起来了
They could be in hiding.
罗柏相信他们还活着
Robb believes they're alive.
他坚信这一点
And he must go on believing.
要打胜仗罗柏必须坚强
He's got to remain strong if he's to prevail.
你为了他也要坚强下去
And you must remain strong for him.
你是罗柏・史塔克的妻子
You're Robb Stark's wife.
别乱动
Hold still.
他们说的他那些事是真的吗？
Is it true what they say about him?
我不知道 他们说他什么？
I don't know. What do they say about him?
说他晚上会变成一头狼
That he can turn into a wolf at night.
是真的
True.
还说他会生吃敌人的血肉
And he eats the flesh of his enemies.
没错
True.
威廉・兰尼斯特
你姓兰尼斯特 是么？
You're a Lannister, aren't you?
马丁・兰尼斯特
Martyn Lannister.
你不必害怕
You've nothing to fear.
我丈夫不吃小孩
My husband doesn't eat children.
除非是满月
Unless it's a full moon.
今天晚上不是满月吧？
It's not a full moon tonight, is it?
看到没？
See?
不必害怕
Nothing to fear.
曼斯・雷德
“塞外之王”
还是这么艺术啊
Always the artists.
只有马的尸体
It's only horses.
琼恩・雪诺
叛逃的乌鸦
没有人的
No men.
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
你不是说有不少死乌鸦嘛
You said there was dead crows.
本来有
There was.
欧瑞尔
“鹰眼” 易形者
一共有多少人
How many men were here?
大约300人
About 300.
你知道这些人现在怎么样吗？
And you know what those men are now?
对异鬼来说我们都一样――他们军队的食物
We're all the same to them-- meat for their army.
你觉得有没有人逃走了？
Do you think anyone got away?
不是不可能
It's not impossible.
莫尔蒙不容轻视
You don't go far betting against Mormont.
但无论是死是活
But dead or alive,
他北上的这一场豪赌
he took a big gamble coming north.
都已失败
And he lost.
他手下最能打的人全都死了
His best fighting men are dead.
不管他是守夜人军团的司令官
And whether he's Lord Commander of the Night's Watch
还是一具蓝眼睛的尸体
or a blue-eyed corpse,
他都离长城远得很
he's a long way from home.
托蒙德
Tormund.
翻过长城
Climb the Wall.
带上欧瑞尔 挑20个好手
Take Orell and 20 good men.
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人掠袭者
把他也带上
And take this one.
黑城堡的防御他比我们所有人都熟
He knows Castle Black's defenses better than any of us.
如果他有用 那当然好 否则……
And if he's useful, good. If not...
把他从城墙上扔下去
throw him off the Wall.
看看乌鸦到底会不会飞
See if crows can fly.
终于要打仗了吗 老朋友？
We're finally going to war, old friend?
在黑城堡附近藏起来
Hide near Castle Black.
收到我的信号之后 趁晚上偷袭他们
When I give the signal, hit them in the night.
他们可以依着巨大的长城防守
They've got a big old wall to hide behind,
但是长城只能防守北面
but it only guards one side.
- 我们会再见面的 - 没错
- We'll meet again. - Aye.
- 只要你事情办妥了 - 哈
- If you do your job. - Ah.
我们怎么收到你的信号？
How will we see your signal?
每天晚上让你的鹰飞到长城上方
Send your eagle above the Wall every night.
时机到了 我会点燃北境所见过的
When it's time, I'm going to light the biggest fire
最大的一团火焰
the North has ever seen.
山姆威尔・塔利
守夜人事务官
白灵？
Ghost?
白灵
琼恩・雪诺的冰原狼
瞧瞧这是什么？冻僵的乌鸦？
What have we here? Frozen crows?
我们赶了很远的路
We've come a long way.
比你来时少了很多人啊
Smaller flock than you went north with.
我们可以进去谈
We can talk inside.
杰奥・莫尔蒙
“熊老” 守夜人总司令
哦 是吗？
Oh, can we?
卡斯特
野人
葛兰
守夜人游骑兵
他们需要些水
They need some water.
把它拴起来 我马上进来
Tether it and I'll be inside.
雷斯特
守夜人
管好你们的眼睛
Keep your eyes where they belong.
她们不是你能看的
They're not for you.
我敢说你喂猪的食物也比给我们的好
Bet you feed that pig better than you feed us.
没错 猪对我来说有用
Aye, pig's got value to me.
我让你们进来你们就该亲我的脚了
You should all be kissing my feet for letting you in.
如果我不是个信神的人我早让你们全滚蛋了
I'd have turned you all away if I wasn't a godly man.
你信神？
You are a godly man?
是的 我不害怕外面发生什么
I am. I got no fear of what's out there.
当白色寒神来临时
When the white cold comes,
你们的剑和斗篷还有他妈的火堆都帮不了你
your swords and cloaks and bloody fires won't help you.
只有信对了神的人才能活下来
The only ones left will be those who are right with the gods.
信奉真神的人
The real gods.
去告诉她 要么咬个破布
Go tell her she can bite down on a rag
要么就等着我的拳头
or she can bite down on my fist.
女人
Women.
那只母猪就在那
That sow right there gave birth
生了八只小猪
to a litter of eight.
都没哼哼一下
Barely a grunt.
她也就跟这家伙差不多肥
And she's almost as fat as this one here.
艾迪森・托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪”  守夜人事务官
你们怎么不吃了他？
Now why don't you dine on him?
走的时候切下几块来带走
Carve off what you need as you go.
看看他 根本就是会走路的美食嘛
Well, look at him. He's a walking feast.
快了快了
Here we are.
给我磨锋利点 好吗？
Sharpen these for me, would ya?
我看到头了 用力
I see the head. Push.
很好
That's it.
就快生出来了
You're nearly there.
吉莉
卡斯特的女儿与妻子
再用点力就生出来了
One more push should do it.
男孩女孩？男孩女孩？
What is it? What is it?
别做声
Keep quiet.
席恩・葛雷乔伊
铁群岛继承人
如果你不能骑马 我们就完了
If you can't ride, we don't stand a chance.
我能骑
I can ride.
你确定？
You're sure?
往东骑 跟着升起的太阳
Ride east. Follow the rising sun.
你姐姐在等着你
Your sister's waiting for you.
我会报答你的 我会封你做铁群岛的头领
I'll make you a Lord of the Iron Islands for this.
我们可不在铁群岛
We're not in the Iron Islands.
- 快走 - 驾
- Go. - Come on.
驾 驾
Come on. Come on.
等等
Come on back.
你不打算告诉我你要去哪？
You refuse to tell me where you're going?
我还不知道 圣火会指示我的
I don't know yet. The fires will show me.
- 你会去多久？ - 我不知道
- How long will you be gone? - I don't know.
你要抛弃我
You're abandoning me.
我绝对不会抛弃你
I will never abandon you.
史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
狭海中的王
你是圣焰之子
You are the Son of Fire.
- 我发誓效忠于你  - 那就留下
- I am sworn to serve you. - Then serve me.
当我回来的时候 你会明白的
When I return, you will understand.
敌人认为我已经被彻底击败了
My enemies think they've destroyed me.
他们在嘲笑我
They're laughing at me
像蓝礼那样嘲笑我
the way Renly laughed at me.
我要乔佛里死
I want Joffrey dead.
我要罗柏・史塔克死
I want Robb Stark dead.
梅丽珊卓
光之王的“红袍祭司”
再给我生个孩子
Make me another son.
我不能
I cannot.
为什么？
Why?
你的力量不足 这会害死你的
You don't have the strength. It would kill you.
我没有那么容易死 人们想杀我很久了
I'm not so easily killed. Men have been trying for years.
我想要你
I want you.
你的火焰燃烧得很微弱 国王陛下
Your fires burn low, my king.
还有其它的办法 更好的办法
There is another way. A better way.
你说过你的魔法需要国王之血才能施放
You told me your magic requires a king's blood.
- 是的 - 而我是唯一真正的国王
- Yes. - I'm the one true king.
您的确是
You are.
但是还有人的血管里 也流淌着您的血
But there are others with your blood in their veins.
您终将称王于铁王座
You will sit on the Iron Throne,
但在此之前 必须要做出牺牲
but first there must be sacrifices.
光之王需要祭品
The Lord of Light demands it.
这条惩罚之路是一个警告 陛下
The Walk of Punishment is a warning, Your Grace.
- 给谁的警告？ - 那些胆敢犯罪的奴隶
- To whom? - To any slave who contemplates doing
他们的下场便是如此
whatever these slaves did.
丹妮莉丝・坦格利安
风暴降生 龙之母
水
Give me your water.
卡丽熙 这人是个死刑犯
Khaleesi, this man has been sentenced to death.
来 喝一点
Here, drink.
离开这儿吧 陛下
Leave this place, Your Grace.
今晚就走 我恳求您
Leave tonight, I beg you.
巴利斯坦・赛尔弥
女王铁卫 “无畏的”
乔拉・莫尔蒙
“大熊” 熊老之子
那招兵的事儿怎么办？
And what is she to do for soldiers?
我们可以在潘托斯和密尔找到雇佣兵
We can find sellswords in Pentos and Myr.
你已经开始说“我们”了 巴利斯坦爵士？
Is it "we" already, Ser Barristan?
如果想重回祖先的王座 您只能武力夺取
If you want to sit on the throne your ancestors built, you must win it.
这意味着在此之前 您的手上将会沾满鲜血
That will mean blood on your hands before the thing is done.
沾满敌人的血 而不是无辜者的
The blood of my enemies, not the blood of innocents.
你打过几次仗 巴利斯坦爵士？
How many wars have you fought in, Ser Barristan?
- 三次 - 有哪次
- Three. - Have you ever seen a war
没有牺牲成千上万的无辜者？
where innocents didn't die by the thousands?
君临陷落的时候我在场 卡丽熙
I was in King's Landing after the sack, khaleesi.
你猜我看到了什么？ 屠杀
You know what I saw? Butchery.
婴儿 孩童 老人全都惨遭毒手
Babies, children, old men.
遭强暴的妇女更是无法尽数
More women raped than you can count.
每个人心中都有一头狂暴的野兽
There's a beast in every man
只要武器交到他手中 那头野兽便会蠢蠢欲动
and it stirs when you put a sword in his hand.
但无垢者不是人
But the Unsullied are not men.
他们不会强暴妇女
They do not rape.
除非指挥官明确下令 他们不会劫掠城市
They do not put cities to the sword unless they're ordered to do so.
如果您买下他们 他们会只杀您想杀的人
If you buy them, the only men they'll kill are those you want dead.
你不这样认为吗 巴利斯坦爵士？
Do you disagree, Ser Barristan?
当您的兄长雷加 率领军队在三叉戟河作战时
When your brother Rhaegar led his army into battle at the Trident,
人们为他而死 是因为他们信任他
men died for him because they believed in him,
因为他们爱他
because they loved him,
而非因为他拍卖会上出价最高
not because they'd been bought at a slaver's auction.
那一天 我曾与最后的真龙并肩作战 陛下
I fought beside the last dragon on that day, Your Grace.
我为他而负伤
I bled beside him.
雷加战斗得英勇 雷加战斗得高贵
Rhaegar fought valiantly, Rhaegar fought nobly,
雷加死得不明不白
and Rhaegar died.
你很了解雷加吗 巴利斯坦爵士？
Did you know him well, Ser Barristan?
是的 陛下 他是我见过的最好的人
I did, Your Grace. Finest man I ever met.
我希望我也能认识他
I wish I had known him.
但他并非最后的真龙
But he was not the last dragon.
所有的？
All?
小人听错了吗 陛下？
Did this one's ears mishear, Your Grace?
你没有 我要买下所有的无垢者
They did not. I want to buy them all.
她想把他们全买下来
格雷赞
阿斯塔波的奴隶主
克拉兹尼・莫・纳克罗兹
弥桑黛
奴隶翻译
她买不起
这荡妇以为给我们瞅瞅她的奶子
就能予取予夺了
阿斯塔波一共有8000名无垢者
There are 8,000 Unsullied in Astapor.
这就是您指的“所有的”？
Is this what you mean by all?
是的 8000名
Yes. 8,000.
仍在训练中的也包括在内
And the ones still in training as well.
要是他们打了败仗
阿斯塔波会蒙羞的
格雷赞主人说他们不能出售未完成训练的男孩
Master Greizhen says they cannot sell half-trained boys.
如果他们在战场上失败
If they fail on the battlefield,
那会让整个阿斯塔波的名声受损
they will bring shame upon all of Astapor.
如果你们不全数卖给我 我就一个也不买
I will have them all or take none.
如果他们在战斗中死亡
Many will fall in battle.
我需要那些男孩作为替补继续战斗
I'll need the boys to pick up the swords they drop.
这荡妇钱不够全买下
克拉兹尼主人说您付不起这么多钱
Master Kraznys says you cannot afford this.
她的船够买100个无垢者 不能再多了
您的船可以换来100名无垢者
Your ship will buy you 100 Unsullied.
这还是因为我喜欢她臀部的线条
这还是出于克拉兹尼主人的慷慨大方
Because Master Kraznys is generous.
剩下的财物还够买10个
您剩下的金子只能买下10名
The gold you have left is worth 10.
她别像白痴一样哭哭啼啼我就给她算成20个
但善良的克拉兹尼主人会卖给您20名
But good Master Kraznys will give you 20.
她那群多斯拉克人闻起来像屎
您带领的多斯拉克人――
The Dothraki you have with you--
拿来喂猪倒可能不错
您带领的多斯拉克人 还不如他们吃掉的东西有价值
The Dothraki you have are not worth what they cost to feed,
也就再值3个
但是克拉兹尼主人会用3名无垢者
but Master Kraznys will give you three Unsullied
来交换这些人
for all of them.
所以问问这个讨饭的女王
剩下7877名无垢者的价格
for the remaining 7,877 Unsullied.
剩下的7877个她打算怎么买
我还有龙 我可以给你们一条
I have dragons. I'll give you one.
您应当用龙 而非奴隶 来夺回王座 陛下
You will win the throne with dragons, not slaves, Your Grace.
卡丽熙 求求您
Khaleesi, please.
我要三条龙
Three dragons.
- 一条 - 两条
- One. - Two.
一条
One.
他们想要最大的那一条
They want the biggest one.
- 成交 - 成交
- Done. - Done.
我还要把你也带走 就现在
I'll take you as well, now.
克拉兹尼主人想要知道您想如何支付
Master Kraznys asks how you propose to pay
你将会是克拉兹尼主人送给我的礼物
You'll be Master Kraznys' gift to me.
一个讨价还价的战利品
A token of a bargain well struck.
她要求把我作为礼物送给她
她现在就要
卡丽熙 一条龙的价值比任何军队都高
Khaleesi, a dragon is worth more than any army.
伊耿・坦格利安早就证明过这一点
Aegon Targaryen proved that.
你们都是来给我出谋划策的
You're both here to advise me.
我重视你们的建议 但如果你们再次
I value your advice, but if you ever question me
在他人面前质疑我
in front of strangers again,
你们就另谋高就吧
you'll be advising someone else.
明白了吗？
Is that understood?
你有名字吗？
Do you have a name?
小人名叫弥桑黛 陛下
This one's name is Missandei, Your Grace.
你有家人吗？如果可能回家的话
Do you have a family? A mother and a father
有在家等你的父母吗？
you'd return to if you had the choice?
没有 陛下 我的家人都不在了
No, Your Grace. No family living.
那从现在起你属于我了 你的职责就是告诉我真相
You belong to me now. It is your duty to tell me the truth.
是的 陛下 欺骗是重罪
Yes, Your Grace. Lying is a great offense.
很多惩罚之路上的罪人 犯得罪甚至比这要轻得多
Many of those on the Walk of Punishment were taken there for less.
在惩罚之路上 我给了一名濒死的奴隶一些水喝
I offered water to one of the slaves dying on the Walk of Punishment.
你知道他对我说了什么吗？ “让我死吧”
Do you know what he said to me? "Let me die."
死了之后就没有奴隶主虐待他们了 陛下
There are no masters in the grave, Your Grace.
关于无垢者的事情
Is it true what Master Kraznys told me
克拉兹尼说的是真的吗？他们真的绝对服从？
about the Unsullied? About their obedience?
他们不会心生疑虑
All questions have been taken from them.
只会服从 别无二意
They obey, that is all.
一旦被您买下 他们就属于您
Once they are yours, they are yours.
就算您命令他们自杀 他们也会照做
They will fall on their swords if you command it.
那你呢？你知道么 我将把你带入战场
And what about you? You know that I'm taking you to war.
你可能会饿肚子 你可能会生病
You may go hungry. You may fall sick.
你可能会被杀
You may be killed.
Valar morghulis.
是的 男人皆有一死
Yes, all men must die.
但我们是女人
But we are not men.
用这地儿来保管王室账单 还真是出人意料啊
A surprising place to keep the royal ledgers.
你这么惊讶才让真是出人意料
I'm surprised you're surprised.
波德瑞克・派恩
提利昂的侍从
这是全城最安全的地方
This is the safest place in the city.
对于野种来说并非如此吧
Not for bastards.
所有的都在这里了 大人
That's all of them, my lord.
谢谢 亲爱的 波德
Thank you, my dear. Pod.
波德 把它们拿出去
Pod. Take them outside.
- 我随后就会到 - 好的 大人
- I'll be there in a moment. - Yes, my lord.
萝丝
妓女
我听说你欠那个男孩很大一笔债
I hear you owe that boy a significant debt.
我的一条命而已
Only my life.
恐怕没有你说的那么大
Not all that significant, I'm afraid.
你应当封他为骑士
You should have him knighted.
如果财政大臣有这权力 我一定会的
If only the Master of Coin had such power.
如果
If only.
我也欠你很大一笔债
I owe you a significant debt.
我们红头发的朋友
Our redheaded friend.
是你把她从太后手里保释出来的
You secured her release when the queen detained her.
哦 这个啊
Oh, that.
当然了 那只是个小误会
Of course. A simple misunderstanding.
显然 太后陛下认为
Apparently, Her Grace believed
你们二人的关系非同一般
that you two had some sort of special relationship.
我们没有 我干过她一次
We don't. I did fuck her once.
- 我知道 - 但我们没有别的关系
- I know. - But we don't.
我知道
I know.
但为什么太后会这样想？
But how would the queen get that idea?
你怎么不问她呢？
Why don't you ask her?
对于我的新职务 你有什么建议吗？
Any advice for me on my new position?
保持低调
Keep a low profile.
如果每次我听到这个笑话
If I had a gold dragon
都可以得到一枚金龙 我现在就比你更有钱了
for every time I heard that joke, I'd be richer than you are.
你本来就比我更有钱
Well, you are richer than I am.
说得好
Good point.
它们只是数字 纸上的数字
They're only numbers. Numbers on paper.
一旦你理解了这一点 你可以很轻松地控制它们
Once you understand that, it's easy to make them behave.
甚至微不足道
Trivial even.
你想要接受真正的挑战吗？
You want a real challenge?
来尝试一下我的妓女吧
Try whores.
我可没少尝试过
I've tried quite a few.
我还有好多事情要做
Well, lots of work to do.
祝你在鹰巢城过得愉快
Enjoy the Eyrie.
来嘛 我晚点儿再来
Come on, I'm here later.
来嘛
Come on.
我们今晚再见
Tonight, then.
似乎是些很无聊的读物
Looks like dull reading.
在你看来所有的读物都很无聊吧
You think all reading is dull reading.
不只是我 很多色的人都这么想
It's an opinion I share with some of the finest men I know.
波隆
骑士
七国历史上那些不为人知的故事 都藏在这些书页里
The secret history of the Seven Kingdoms is written in these pages.
除非山羊胡大人编造了一串数字
Unless Lord Twatbeard made up a bunch of numbers
来掩盖他的真实目的
to hide what he's really up to.
除非这全是他胡编乱造的 是的
Unless he made it all up, yes.
- 波德瑞克 跟紧我们 - 是的 大人
- Podrick, do keep up. - Yes, my lord.
- 波德瑞克 - 是的 大人？
- Podrick. - Yes, my lord?
在与我的朋友波隆爵士 商量了许久之后
After a long consultation with my colleague Ser Bronn,
我终于想到了一个合适的方法
I finally found a suitable reward
来奖赏你这段时间
for the services you've provided over and above
为我提供的优质服务
what might be considered reasonable.
告诉我 波德
Tell me, Pod,
你曾经和女人睡过吗？
have you ever been with a woman?
- 没有 大人 - 太好了
- No, my lord. - Wonderful.
吉娜最擅长对付处男了
Genna specializes in first-timers.
吉娜
妓女
当然对付非处男也不错
She's not bad with second-timers, either.
呃 大人……
Uh, my lord...
得亏你一枪刺进那人脸窝 救了我的命
A fair enough repayment for putting your spear
这就是给你的奖励 还成吧？
through my would-be killer's face, wouldn't you say?
接下来呢
Now, as it happens,
玛丽……
Marei...
她的身体滑如矛柄
is quite the spear handler herself.
这是为了感谢你在战火纷飞的时候
She's here to thank you for staying by my side
玛丽
妓女
一直守在我的身边
as the battle raged all around me.
他很帅气
He's handsome.
你可没告诉过我他有这么帅气
You didn't tell me he was handsome.
在这个圈子里
Kayla is famous from here to Volantis
凯拉
妓女
凯拉的名气甚至远扬至瓦兰提斯
in certain circles.
她是世上仅有的四位
One of four women in the world
可以完成弥林结的女人之一
who can perform a proper Meereenese Knot.
弥林结：本指困扰作者多年的卷五创作难关，此处为彩蛋
大人 我还是个……
My lord, I don't even...
你总是称呼我为“大人”
She's here to thank you
叫她来是为了感谢
for being a thoroughly respectful fellow
你这样出色的侍从的
who's never once failed to address me as "my lord."
在我进晚餐之前回来
Be back in time for my supper.
悠着点 伙计
Pace yourself, lad.
这些年来我一直听说
For years I've heard that Littlefinger
小指头会变戏法
is a magician.
无论何时国王需要钱 他只消双手一搓
Whenever the crown needs money, he rubs his hands together
吹口气 金山银海就出现了
and, poof, mountains of gold.
让我猜猜 他不会变戏法
Let me guess. He's not a magician.
不会
No.
- 他的钱是偷来的？ - 更糟 是借来的
- He's stealing it? - Worse, he's borrowing it.
那有什么问题？
What's wrong with that?
我们偿还不起 这就是问题所在
We can't afford to pay it back, that's what's wrong with it.
铁王座欠了我父亲几百万金龙
The crown owes millions to my father.
看在他的孙子坐着铁王座的份上
Seeing as it's his grandson's ass on the throne,
我猜他会免除这些债务
I imagine he'll forgive that debt.
免除债务 我的父亲大人？
Forgive a debt, my father?
亏你还能活在这个世上 你还真是出奇的天真
For a man of the world, you're strangely naive.
我以前从来没借过钱
I've never borrowed money before.
我又不懂这方面的道道
I'm not clear on the rules.
那么……
Well...
咳咳！
Ahem!
基本的原则是
The basic principle is
我借给你钱
I lend you money,
在商定的时间过去之后
and after an agreed upon period of time,
你要连本带利的返还给我
you return it with interest.
如果我不还呢？
And what if I don't?
呃 你必须还
Well, you have to.
如果我就是不还呢？
But what if I don't?
这就是为啥我不会借钱给你
This is why I don't lend you money.
总之 我担心的不是我父亲
Anyway, it's not my father I'm worried about.
我担心的是布拉佛斯的铁金库
It's the Iron Bank of Braavos.
我欠了他们几千万金龙
We owe them tens of millions.
如果我们还不上这份债务 铁金库就会赞助我们的敌人
If we fail to repay these loans, the bank will fund our enemies.
无论通过何种手段 他们总会拿回属于他们的钱
One way or another, they always get their gold back.
啊 我们的征服英雄回来了
Ah, the return of the conquering hero.
他是不是刚旅游回来？
Does he have a little jaunt in his step?
这小伙都快跳起舞来了
The lad's practically skipping.
你花了挺长时间
You were gone a long time.
我相信你的钱没白花
I trust you got your money's worth.
或者我应该说我的钱没白花？
Or should I say my money's worth?
哦 这是个礼物 波德瑞克
Oh, it was a gift, Podrick.
这比我一整年给你的都多
This is more than I give you in a year.
他是个侍从 你不用付他钱
He's a squire. You don't pay him.
哦 那这比我一整年给你的要多得多
Oh, then it's much more than I give you in a year.
她们没要钱 大人
They wouldn't take it, my lord.
或许她们想要和新上任的财政大臣
Maybe they're trying to curry some favor
套套近乎
with the new Master of Coin.
你听说过有妓女拒绝金子的吗？
Have you ever known a whore to turn down gold?
只要我给她们 她们就非常开心
They were happy enough to take it when I gave it to them.
你跟她们说什么了？
What did you tell them?
我什么也没说
I didn't tell them anything.
- 你对她们做什么了？ - 挺多花样的
- What did you do to them? - Lots of things.
那她们看上去挺喜欢这些花样的？
And they seemed to like these things?
是的 大人
Yes, my lord.
她们当然会看上去挺喜欢的
Of course they seemed to like it.
付钱就是为了让她们假装喜欢的
They're paid to seem to like it.
但是她们这次没拿钱
Only they weren't paid.
你在说什么呢？姑娘们很喜欢他
What are you saying? These ladies enjoyed him so much,
所以她们这次免费为他服务
they gave him the time for free?
这就是你想说的吗？
Is that what you're telling us?
坐下 波德瑞克
Sit down, Podrick.
我们需要谈谈细节
We're going to need details.
详尽的细节
Copious details.
快！快！
Come on! Come on!
快啊！
Come on!
驾！
Come on.
吓！吓！
Ha! Ha!
逃亡者什么下场 你知道吧？
You know how we deal with runaways here, do you?
脱了他的裤子
Take off his pants.
不要！不要！
No! No!
不 不 不！
No, no, no!
我要把你操进地里
I'm gonna fuck you into the dirt.
不 求你了！不 不 不！
No, please! No, no, no!
不 不要！
No, don't!
不 求你了！
No, please!
不！不！
No! No!
你这小杂种
You little bastard.
来 大人
Come, my lord.
你离家太远了 况且凛冬将至
You're a long way from home and winter is coming.
我要先干那个大个儿婊子
I'll take the big bitch first.
当她又湿又爽的时候 你们就能了结了她
When she's good and wet, you lot can finish her off.
大人 我是塔斯的布蕾妮
My lord, I am Brienne of Tarth.
凯特琳・史塔克夫人命我
Lady Catelyn Stark commanded me
将詹姆爵士送到君临城
to deliver Ser Jaime to King's Landing.
凯特琳・史塔克是个大逆不道的贱人
Catelyn Stark's a treasonous cunt.
上头就吩咐过活捉弑君者
Orders were to take the Kingslayer alive.
没他妈提过你
Nobody said shit about you.
这可是你自找的
You're only making it worse.
把她带到暗处去
Take her over there where it's dark.
我可不想被人看着
I'd like a little privacy.
过来！
Come on!
你知道她是谁 对吧？
You know who she is, don't you?
大个蠢婊子，谁管她哪来的
A big dumb bitch from who cares where.
大到根本算不上是个女人
Never been with a woman that big.
洛奇
她是塔斯的布蕾妮
She's Brienne of Tarth.
塞尔温・塔斯伯爵的女儿
Her father is Lord Selwyn Tarth.
听说过塔斯岛吗？
Heard of Tarth?
我要割了你的喉咙！
I'm gonna cut your throat!
也叫“蓝宝石之岛” 知道为什么吗？
They call it the Sapphire Isle. Do you know why?
维斯特洛的所有蓝宝石
Every sapphire in Westeros
都产自塔斯岛
was mined on Tarth.
蓝宝石是一种宝石
Sapphires are gemstones.
- 蓝色的那种 - 这个我明白
- The blue ones. - I know what they are.
如果你把她送回去
Lord Selwyn would pay his daughter's weight
塞尔温伯爵会付给你和她一样重的蓝宝石作为赎金
in sapphires if she's returned to him.
但必须是活着的
But only if she's alive,
并且清誉无损
her honor unbesmirched.
把她带回这来
Bring her back here.
是 大人
Yes, my lord.
- 起来 - 过来
- Get up. - Come on.
站起来 走过来
Come on, on your feet.
完璧
Unbesmirched.
没破处
Not defiled.
讲究人说讲究话哈
Fancy word for a fancy man.
我小时候很讨厌读书
I hated to read as a child,
但我父亲逼着我每天早上起来念书
but my father forced me to study the books every morning
直到我可以练剑骑马
before I could practice with sword or horse.
每天被闷在学士的屋子里两个小时
Two hours every day holed up in the maester's chambers.
我学了很多文绉绉的语言
I learned a lot of fancy words.
我看也是
I bet you did.
你老爹
Your father,
会付和你一般重的金子赎你回来？
he'd pay your weight in gold to get you back?
你下半辈子都会很富有的
You'll be a rich man till the end of your days.
你的儿子们也会很富有
And your sons will be rich men
你的孙子们也是
and their sons after them.
封地 爵位――
Lands, titles--
都会有的
you'll have them all.
北境赢不了这场战争的
The North can't win this war.
你是个聪明人 你知道这点
You're a smart man. You understand that.
我们兵多将广 我们国库丰盈
We have the numbers. We have the gold.
没错 这俩你们都有
Aye, you have both.
为了一个终将失败的目标奋勇作战
Fighting bravely for a losing cause
是令人钦佩的
is admirable.
为了一个最终胜利的目标作战
Fighting for a winning cause
则有实打实的好处
is far more rewarding.
这倒真得承认
Hard to argue with that.
那我们敞开天窗说亮话
Now that we're speaking together man to man,
我觉得你没必要非把我锁在树上
I wonder if you need to keep me chained to this tree.
我不是要求松绑
I'm not asking to be freed from my constraints,
但如果我能躺着睡下
but if I could sleep lying down,
我的背会很感激的
my back would thank you for it.
我不再像曾经那样
I'm not as young
年轻而有活力了
and resilient as I was once.
我们都不小了
None of us are.
把詹姆爵士从树上放下来
Unchain Ser Jaime from the tree.
来吧 伙计
Come on, men.
我觉得你可能想填填肚子？
Suppose you'll be wanting something to eat.
实际上 我快饿死了
I'm famished, actually.
我想火堆上还多了一只烤鹧鸪
I think we've got a spare partridge on the fire.
呃 我喜欢鹧鸪
Well, I do like partridge.
把那些鸟拿过来 还有切肉刀
Bring the bird over here and the carving knife.
这能当您的餐桌吗 大人？
Will this work as a table, my lord?
哦 好的 好的 这样感觉很――
Oh, yes. Yes, this will do nic--
啊！
ah!
趴上去
On the stump.
你觉得你是这里面脑瓜子最灵光的？
You think you're the smartest man there is.
每个人都得点头哈腰
That everyone alive has to bow and scrape
舔你的靴子
and lick your boots.
- 我父亲―― - 无论你遇上任何麻烦
- My father-- - And if you get in any trouble,
只要报上你父亲的大名
all you've got to do is say "my father"
就能拍屁股走人
and that's it, all your troubles are gone.
- 不要 - 你有什么要说的吗？
- Don't. - Have you got something to say?
小心点 话可别乱说
Careful. You don't want to say the wrong thing.
没你爹你屁都不是
You're nothing without your daddy,
而他恰好不在呢
and your daddy ain't here.
给我记牢了
Never forget that.
这个应该能让你长点记性
Here, this should help you remember.
衣柜字幕组出品
《狗熊和美少女》（The Bear and the Maiden Fair）是七国皆传的粗鄙传统歌曲。歌曲用幽默的口吻讲述了一个多毛的狗熊带着三个男孩和一只山羊去营救一位期待骑士的美少女的故事。
这只狗熊 狗熊 狗熊
A bear there was, a bear, a bear!
全身黑棕 罩着毛绒
All black and brown and covered with hair
男孩 山羊 跳舞的熊
Three boys, a goat, and a dancing bear
边跳边转 慢慢走向美人
They danced and spun right to the fair
她好甜 纯洁 美容
How sweet she was, so pure and fair
蜂蜜在少女发丛
The maid with honey up in her hair
跟随夏日里的气涌
He smelled her all in the summer air
蜂蜜在少女发丛
The maid with honey up in her hair
这头 那弄
From there to here, from here to there
全身黑棕 罩着毛绒
All black and brown and covered in hair
跟随夏日里的气涌
He smelled that girl in the summer air
狗熊 狗熊 少女美容
- The bear, the bear - The maiden fair
噢 我是女孩 纯洁而美容
Oh, I'm a maid and I'm pure and fair
跳舞不跟毛狗熊
I'll never dance with a hairy bear
我呼唤骑士 可你是狗熊
I called a knight, but you're a bear
全身黑棕 罩着毛绒
All black and brown and covered in hair
这头 那弄
From there to here, from here to there
全身黑棕 罩着毛绒
All black and brown and covered in hair
跟随夏日里的气涌
He smelled that girl in the summer air
狗熊 狗熊 少女美容
- The bear, the bear - The maiden fair.